blurgroup.com 2017-06-03

# Privacy & Cookie Policy | blur Group

We use cookies and similar tools across our websites to improve their performance and enhance your user experience. This policy explains how we do that.

### What are cookies?

Cookies are small text files which a website may put on your computer or mobile device when you first visit a site or page. The cookie will help the website, or another website, to recognise your device the next time you visit. Web beacons or other similar files can also do the same thing. We use the term “cookies” in this policy to refer to all files that collect information in this way. There are many functions cookies serve. For example, they can help us to remember your username and preferences, analyse how well our website is performing. Certain cookies contain personal information – for example, if you click to “remember me” when logging in, a cookie will store your username. Most cookies won’t collect information that identifies you, and will instead collect more general information such as how users arrive at and use our websites, or a user’s general location.

### Essential Cookies

Some cookies are essential for the operation of our website. For example, some cookies allow us to identify customers and ensure they can access the account only pages. If a customer opts to disable these cookies, the user will not be able to access all of the content in their account.

### Does anyone else use cookies on blur Group websites?

We also use or allow third parties to serve cookies that fall into the four categories above. For example, like many companies, we use Google Analytics to help us monitor our website traffic. We may also use third party cookies to help us with market research, revenue tracking, improving site functionality and monitoring compliance with our terms and conditions and copyright policy.

### Can a website user block cookies?

Cookies help you to get the most out of our websites. The first time you accessed our website you should have seen an overlay which explained that by continuing to access our site, you are consenting to our use of cookies. However, if you do wish to disable our cookies then please follow the instructions on our "How to Manage Cookies" page. Please remember that if you do choose to disable cookies, you may find that certain sections of our website do not work properly.

### Do we track whether users open our emails?

Our emails may contain a single, campaign-unique “web beacon pixel” to tell us whether our emails are opened and verify any clicks through to links or advertisements within the email. We may use this information for purposes including determining which of our emails are more interesting to users, to query whether users who do not open our emails wish to continue receiving them and to inform our advertisers in aggregate how many users have clicked on their advertisements. The pixel will be deleted when you delete the email. If you do not wish the pixel to be downloaded to your device, you should select to receive emails from us in plain text rather than HTML.

### More Information

More detail on how businesses use cookies is available at allaboutcookies If you have any queries regarding this Cookie Policy please contact our Privacy Officer by e-mail at [info@blurgroup.com](mailto:info@blurgroup.com)

As we explain in our Cookie Policy, cookies help you to get the most out of our websites. If you do disable our cookies you may find that certain sections of our website do not work. For example, you may have difficulties logging in or viewing articles.

### Google Chrome

  * Click the wrench icon on the browser toolbar
  * Select Settings
  * Click ‘Show advanced settings’
  * In the “Privacy” section, click the ‘Content settings’ button
  * To enable cookies in the “Cookies” section, pick ‘Allow local data to be set’, this will enable both first-party and third-party cookies. To allow only first-party cookies pick ‘Block all third-party cookies without exception’
  * To disable cookies, in the “Cookies” section, pick ‘Block sites from setting any data’
  * Note there are various levels of cookie enablement and disablement in Chrome. For more information on other cookie settings offered in Chrome, refer to the following page from [here](https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/95647?hl=en)

### Microsoft Internet Explorer 6.0, 7.0, 8.0

  * Click on 'Tools' at the top of your browser window and select 'Internet Options'
  * In the options window navigate to the 'Privacy' tab
  * To enable cookies: Set the slider to ‘Medium’ or below
  * To disable cookies: Move the slider to the top to block all cookies
  * Note there are various levels of cookie enablement and disablement in Explorer. For more information on other cookie settings offered in Internet Explorer, refer to the following page from [here](http://windows.microsoft.com/en-GB/windows-vista/Block-or-allow-cookies)

### Mozilla Firefox

  * Click on 'Tools' at the browser menu and select ‘Options’
  * Select the Privacy panel
  * To enable cookies: Check ‘Accept cookies for sites’
  * To disable cookies: Uncheck ‘Accept cookies for sites’
  * Note there are various levels of cookie enablement and disablement in Firefox. For more information, refer to the following page from [here](http://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/enable-and-disable-cookies-website-preferences?redirectlocale=en-US&redirectslug=Enabling+and+disabling+cookies)

### Opera

  * Click on 'Setting’ at the browser menu and select 'Settings'
  * Select ‘Quick Preferences’
  * To enable cookies: check “Enable Cookies”
  * To disable cookies: uncheck “Enable Cookies”
  * Note there are various levels of cookie enablement and disablement in Opera. For more information on other cookie settings offered in Opera, refer to the following page from [here](http://www.opera.com/help/tutorials/security/privacy/)

### Safari on OSX

  * Click on 'Safari' at the menu bar and select the 'Preferences' option
  * Click on 'Security'
  * To enable cookies: In the 'Accept cookies' section select 'Only from site you navigate to'
  * To disable cookies: In the ‘Accept cookies’ section select ‘Never’
  * Note there are various levels of cookie enablement and disablement in Safari. For more information on other cookie settings offered in Safari, refer to the following page from Apple: All other browsers, Please look for a “help” function in the browser or contact the browser provider.

### Privacy Policy

Our sites contain links to third party sites which are not subject to this privacy policy. We recommend that you read the privacy policy of any such sites that you visit.

### Information Collected

Personal information is collected by blur Group. References in this privacy policy to “blur Group”, “we”, “us”, “our” or similar refer to blur Group operating the relevant website and references to “blur Group sites” refer to any of our websites from which you have accessed this privacy policy.

Company: blur Group Registered Office: Studio 2, Westbourne Studios, 242 Acklam Road, London, W10 5JJ Registered Number: 06211244. 

We collect personally identifiable information about you (your "Data") through:

  * the use of enquiry and registration forms
  * your purchase of any our products or services
  * the provision of your details to us either online or offline.

The elements of your Data that we collect may include:

  * Name
  * Job title
  * Company name
  * Company address, phone and fax number
  * Home address and phone number
  * Mobile telephone number
  * E-mail address
  * Payment details such as credit card information
  * Date of birth
  * Educational history, work experience and other information from your CV if you provide this to us
  * Market research data such as readership patterns
  * Usage statistics

We may also collect information that we request from you regarding your use of our service or that we collect automatically about your visit to our sites. Please see our Cookies Policy for more details.

### Use and Disclosure of Personal Information

We use your Data for purposes which may include:

  * providing our users with a personalised service
  * processing orders, registrations and enquiries
  * conducting market research surveys
  * allowing users to participate in interactive features of our service, where they choose to do so
  * providing reports to our customers
  * providing you with information about products and services we offer (if you agree to receive such information)
  * monitoring compliance with our Terms and Conditions and Copyright Policy See our Cookies Policy for more details. If you wish to receive information about blur Group products or services or from other carefully selected organisations about products or services they offer, please indicate your preferences using the consent boxes when providing us with your Data. We may also disclose your information to business partners and to third party suppliers we engage to provide services which involve processing data on our behalf, successors in title to our business or in accordance with a properly executed court order or as otherwise required to do so by law. We reserve the right to fully co-operate with any law enforcement authorities or court order requiring or requesting us to disclose the identity or other usage details of any user of our sites. We also use information in aggregate form (so that no individual user is identified by name):
  * to build up marketing profiles
  * to aid strategic development
  * to audit usage of the site. We use technology on the registration and manage my account pages of some of our websites, which may record user movements, including page scrolling, mouse clicks and text entered. It will not record financial information such as credit or debit card details. The data we collect in this way helps us to identify usability issues, to improve the assistance and technical support we can provide to users and is also used for aggregated and statistical reporting purposes.

### Use of Cookies and Other Tracking Devices

Please refer to our Cookies Policy.

### Security Policy

blur Group has appropriate measures in place to ensure that our users’ Data is protected against unauthorised access or use, alteration, unlawful or accidental destruction and accidental loss. User Data may be transferred outside blur Group to data processors such as fulfilment houses but they will act only on our instructions to provide the services required.

### Transfer of Data

The Internet is a global environment. Using the Internet to collect and process personal data necessarily involves the transmission of data on an international basis. Therefore, by browsing blur Group sites and communicating electronically with us you acknowledge and agree to our processing of personal data in this way. By agreeing to our transfer of your Data to third party organisations for them to send you details of products and services offered (as detailed above) you are deemed to provide your consent to any transfer of your Data to organisations based outside the European Economic Area.

### User Access and Control of Data

If you wish to amend any of the Data which we hold about you, or update your marketing preferences, please contact [info@blurgroup.com](mailto:info@blurgroup.com). In accordance with the Data Protection Act 1998, you may request a copy of the personal information we hold about you by contacting the Privacy Officer by e-mail at [info@blurgroup.com](mailto:info@blurgroup.com) or write to:

Company Secretary blur Group Gresham Court, Station Road, Wendens Ambo, Essex, CB11 4LG

We may charge the statutory allowable fee for provision of this information.

### Children Under 14

This policy is effective from May 2012. From time to time we may make changes to this privacy policy statement to reflect any changes to our privacy practices in accordance with changes to legislation, best practice or website enhancements.
